<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Beacon</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>The Buckley Program offers a speaker series, conferences, Firing Line debates, funded summer internships and more. Its mission is to promote intellectul diversity at Yale.</description>


    <atom:link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
      <item>
        <title>Defending the Family</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Editors’ note: Last fall, the Buckley Program sponsored an essay contest open to student Fellows and others within the Yale community. The topic question, tied to our annual conference, was “What is a 21st Century Conservative?” Judged by three Yale professors, the following essay was written by Dimitri Halikias, a rising junior in Ezra Stiles and Operations Director of the Buckley Program. He won the first-place prize of $1,000.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Following Mitt Romney’s defeat last November, liberal and conservative pundits alike rushed to call for a radical rethinking of the Republican Party platform. They charged that conservatism has grown outmoded, with nothing left to offer an increasingly secular, liberal America of the twenty-first century. These criticisms are not without their merit, and they remind us that while it remains committed to absolute moral principles, conservatism as a political theory must remain firmly grounded in reality. Even the most ancient of truths require modern articulations. The project of the twenty-first-century conservative, therefore, is to promote the transcendent principles of human flourishing and virtue, but to do so in a society that can and must continue to evolve. But relying upon such platitudes alone is the mark of progressive or postmodern thought, not conservatism. Modern conservatives must not be afraid to recognize the clear battle of the day—the defense of the bedrock of civilization and culture: the family.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Much to its detriment, the conservative movement in America has relegated the family to the realm of “social” conservatism, ignoring its centrality as a mechanism of economic and political stability. In modern political discourse, “family conservatism” has become a buzzword for “the war on women” on the left and “traditional marriage” on the right. Meanwhile, “sensible” conservatives feel more comfortable discussing national deficits and economic growth rather than to address the crisis of falling marriage rates and a collapse of marital culture. This is an alarming trend in American conservatism. Forgetting the significance of strong families and vibrant communities, conservatives become nothing more than soft liberals, debating meaningless points regarding corporate tax rates and regulations while doing nothing as the very fabric of American society falls apart.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The defense of the family must be picked up anew by twenty-first-century conservatives, and its defense must return to the center of any and all reform agendas. Conservatives should fight to uphold the importance of marriage and the accompanying norms of monogamy and permanence that are necessary for a free and virtuous people. At the same time, conservatives must recognize that the state can be used as a tool to help strengthen and defend the family. Tax policy should be overhauled to eliminate distortions and preferences that do nothing more than subsidize middle- and upper-class expenditures. But at the same time, conservatives should pay heed to proposals like that of Senator Mike Lee to expand child tax credits to support parents struggling to maintain a family in a stagnant economy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Welfare must be reformed to guarantee its economic sustainability but, even more importantly, to eliminate leviathan programs that perpetuate poverty and create a permanent underclass of citizens. It must be recognized that poverty is not only an individual affliction but one that destroys families and communities alike. Conservatives should continue to vehemently oppose all government policies that target faith-based institutions both to defend religious freedom and also as recognition of the invaluable support churches, synagogues, and temples provide for a family structure that secular culture often devalues. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A revival of strong family culture would mean many things for a struggling American society. The family, as Professor Robert P. George often observes, is the original department of education, health, and human services. And as recent literature on economic inequality and social mobility clearly demonstrates, children who grow up in broken families are all but destined for lives of poverty, crime, and abandonment. Abandoning the family and focusing exclusively on the task of ever-faster economic growth and the maximization of personal autonomy will breed nothing but greater disillusionment and chaos in an increasingly fragmented culture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A great deal of ink has been shed diagnosing the calamity of modern conservatism. These are important and valuable debates to be had by any intellectual movement, and there are many fresh and bold thinkers prepared to take the reins of the conservative movement. But conservatives must remain wary of the allure of libertarian “big-tent conservatism,” which purports to appeal to left and right alike in building the conservatism of the future. Combining the principles of 1960s liberationism, non-intervention abroad, and an unfettered free market, an increasingly libertarian conservatism would be left intellectually bereft, unable to make the philosophical case against the dangers of progressivism and relegated to debate the trivial distinction between a 35% and 39.6% top marginal tax rate. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Twenty-first-century conservatives must unite around the family as the fundamental building block of our culture and civilization. They must advocate for marriage as a comprehensive union, while shedding the image of intolerance and bigotry. They must fight for extensive economic reforms, but must recognize that lower taxes and reduced spending are important not as ends in themselves but as means to creating a healthy, vibrant civil society. And they must reenter the culture war to defend the strength of the family and the virtues of the American community that are essential to the wellbeing of the Republic.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jun 2014 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>/culture/2014/06/17/defending-the-family/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/culture/2014/06/17/defending-the-family/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Enduring Truths of Man</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Editors’ note: Last fall, the Buckley Program sponsored an essay contest open to student Fellows and others within the Yale community. The topic question, tied to our annual conference, was “What is a 21st Century Conservative?” Judged by three Yale professors, the following essay was written by Courtney Hodrick, a rising junior in Saybrook. She won the second-place prize of $500.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some things never change. As we find ourselves firmly ensconced within the second decade of the twenty-first century, we may be tempted to say that the world has changed irrevocably, and that our values must change to accommodate it. We would make a grave error in doing so, for even as the shiny tendrils of technological progress wrap us in their embrace, the essential undercurrents of humanity run steady and true as always. Increasingly, to be a conservative is to recognize this fact: to refuse to allow changes to the environments in which we relate to change how we relate, and to protect that which allows us to achieve an intrinsically human greatness. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the more traditional aspects of this quest requires conservatives to continue asserting the importance of economic freedoms. In opposition to those who would seek to label everything from universal healthcare to Internet access as fundamental human rights, and who call on our governments to strong-arm their citizens into leveling the economic playing field and providing these services to those who cannot afford them, conservatives retain their faith in man’s ability to change his own circumstances through perseverance, hard work, and talent. Moreover, we must be willing to do more than just declare, as some Republican political candidates would, that the free markets can redistribute resources better than an expansive state. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead, we must be unafraid to admit that we value man’s freedom to distribute the products of his own labor, even if such distribution inevitably leads to inequality. While liberals use a moral obligation to help the poor as justification for the ever-encroaching nanny state, and for those less fortunate to consider themselves entitled to material luxuries, conservatives reject the idea that we must outsource the enforcement of such morals to governments armed with the power to tax. Instead, we embrace the belief that the choice to do good is only honorable if it is in fact a choice, and the correlated belief that the admirability of one’s material success depends on how much one has accomplished without external assistance. Still, conservatives should share the left’s concern that giant businesses have eroded our relationship to the goods we use, the foods we eat, and most importantly to the people who create them, and should embrace our unlikely allies in the quest to restore local traditions of sustainable farming and artisanship. Further, we must not conflate the freedom to pursue economic ends with a rampant accumulation of material possessions and a glorification of conspicuous consumption.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This temptation to succumb to materialism stems from the loss of meaningful standards by which to judge a man’s life—a loss that has bred a set of beliefs even more insidious than the fallacy that the measure of a man is the sum of his degrees, his net worth, and his possessions. Our modern culture has come to see the scientific prolongation of human life as an end in and of itself, without asking what purpose the extra five, ten, or fifty years ought serve. In the absence of a concept of virtue, it has made an idol of healthfulness, creating a culture of people swapping one trendy “superfruit” for another without stopping to seek truth or fulfillment. Or, if they seek fulfillment, it is only the fulfillment that a man who conceives of himself as a machine designed for no greater purpose than the maximization of dopamine and serotonin can find. The modern glorification of science has reduced man to his chemical components, and the modern man has been convinced that the ideal life is no more than a problem to be solved, a set of functions and reactions to be optimized. The beauty to be found in pain, the necessity of living as if one’s choices reflect one’s values rather than merely following the instructions of the armchair neuroscientists, and the understanding that our differing psychological responses are not the symptoms of our diseases but rather our very selves: All these have been sacrificed at the altar of a misguided quest to understand and control the human through his body. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Conservatives reject this conception of the human, and call for man to seek the aesthetic and moral truth that is to be found in artistic, literary, and philosophical masterpieces. We unabashedly revel in the glory of our cultural zeniths and will not dismantle the canon merely because of the race or gender of its creators. Instead, we will decry the hypocrisy of those who divide our population into identity and interest groups with the stated goal of achieving equal opportunity and the implied goal of achieving a world full of equally atomized individuals leading equally meaningless lives. Conservatives understand that to be born human is to be born into a community and a culture—a tradition and a set of values—and we will not allow the pursuit of false equality to prevent us from holding ourselves and each other to the standards that have been set by the past. In a world in which communication is increasingly reduced to sharing the latest Buzzfeed article and in which there is no word dirtier than “judgmental,” to be a conservative is to seek or affirm a community with value judgments and standards that demands that we live up to them.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jun 2014 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>/philosophy/2014/06/16/the-enduring-truths-of-man/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/philosophy/2014/06/16/the-enduring-truths-of-man/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Our Conservative Roots</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Editors’ note: Last fall, the Buckley Program sponsored an essay contest open to student Fellows and others within the Yale community. The topic question, tied to our annual conference, was “What is a 21st Century Conservative?” Judged by three Yale professors, the following essay was written by Christian Vazquez, member of the Class of 2013 and a former Buckley Fellow. He won the third-place prize of $250.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Liberty must be limited in order to be possessed.”&lt;/em&gt; —Edmund Burke&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Edmund Burke’s words ring just as true in 2013 as they did in 1774. At its core, conservatism will remain the same—its intent and impetus being the same today as when Burke was writing over two centuries before. Conservatism is an optimistic belief in the capacity of mankind and the individual. Nevertheless, it is not foolhardy enough to entrust extreme liberty in the outright. It is true compassion, not a detached product of a system produced en masse to render standard results to all. It is the cautionary and wary eye of progress, not a limiting or counter-progressive instrument—rather, the strategic force by which society moves forward in the most logical and functional manner. Conservatism is not conformity; it is far from it. To be conservative one must counter the tide of popular notions. Populism and unlimited liberty have given us the worst tides of bloodshed in the form of the French and Bolshevik Revolutions and have produced ideologies that stifled liberty to a degree even greater than the very shackles they attempted to throw off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;President Abraham Lincoln once wrote that conservatism is “the adherence to the old and tried, against the new and untried.” I believe that such a definition is the most accurate and encompasses the ideas posed by Burke best. This commitment to what has already been known to function has constrained the tides of revolution and chaos in our own American society. The New World societies of Latin America all attempted radical governments much closer to those of Robespierre than Washington but generated societies much less “free” than our very own. The American Revolution that our founding fathers started over two and a half centuries ago was itself a limited one. It did not attempt to foster a wide range of liberties unbeknownst to eighteenth-century society, partly out of a need for consistency, for the states would not have held together without this conservative approach. They would have prematurely devolved into microstates, different issues would have torn apart the Union, and it would have been stillborn. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From a historical perspective, liberty would never have been attained in America had it not been for the cautious and limiting status of our founding documents. One cannot help but note how absolutely different Philadelphia in 1787 was from Paris in 1789. The Constitutional Convention resulted in the creation of a document that still exists and guides our national life to this day because of its utter conservatism. While drafted by a small circle of elite, it granted enough liberty to allow for it to become increasingly inclusive as to whom it empowered. It did not outright give every citizen the right to vote; in fact, it was quite limiting in those respects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the case could not have been anymore different in France. The Tennis Court Oath brought into existence a National Assembly that was an absolutely radical reimagining of the French social order. This same body would later overthrow the French monarchy and persecute its citizens in a manner of the most violent. A simple restructuring of the social order by integrating the three estates devolved into mob rule within three years. It was the angry French mobs that would call for the guillotine to be sated by the blood of thousands—not the structure that supposedly controlled it. The unbridled liberty unleashed after the storming of the Tuileries was without control. Marat, one of the most vocal supporters of the masses was a victim of the lack of order that was the product of liberty without limits. The revolution had not only severed the French from an authoritarian monarchy, it had also unhinged them from reality. The newly fashioned religion and calendar created by the Directory were symptomatic of an Orwellian society centuries before Orwell’s existence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is no surprise that by taking the course of radical reform, the French were then subjected to empire under Napoleon and numerous restorations of Bourbon leaders. As a result, the French are on their fifth republic and their fifteenth constitution. Our conservative revolution produced a singular constitution, one that has been amended but remains, in its essence, the same. Likewise, our society continues to be more fluid, with a greater chance for progress and betterment. This is a society in which a family can migrate a generation before and send their child to a top tier university. We’ve arrived here because of the conservative nature of our nation’s inception. America is a land of opportunity because of these limits, which themselves created the conditions that allowed for a stable and functioning system to eventually expand those very limits. But first, the center must hold. It is this inherent conservative principle that made us great. America has never allowed wanton populism to rule the day but rather a guided tradition. Conservatism in the twenty-first century will look very much the same in this sense. It is up to conservatives in our century, just as much as in 1955, to “stand athwart history, yelling Stop, at a time when no one is inclined to do so, or to have much patience with those who so urge it.”&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 15 Jun 2014 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>/history,/philosophy/2014/06/15/our-conservative-roots/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/history,/philosophy/2014/06/15/our-conservative-roots/</guid>
      </item>
    


  </channel>
</rss>
