<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Beacon</title>
    <description>The William F. Buckley, Jr. Program was founded in 2010 by a group of Yale undergraduates under the guidance of Professor Donald Kagan. Our mission is to promote intellectual diversity on Yale&#39;s campus.</description>
    <link>/</link>
    <atom:link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
      <item>
        <title>The importance of values</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Let’s remember the importance of values..LJDFGLDJKHFglsdkhgflkshdgfljahsdgfljhvdfksjhvLJDSHVfljhsfbljhsdvljhvljhvljhvfljhvsd&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jun 2014 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>/philosophy/2014/06/10/welcome-to-jekyll/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/philosophy/2014/06/10/welcome-to-jekyll/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Freedom is priceless</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I think we need one &lt;em&gt;thing&lt;/em&gt;, and that thing is &lt;strong&gt;freedom&lt;/strong&gt;. dfajhgsfdkjahdsgfkjhadsgfkjhasdbfkjhgadskfjhgkfdsajhgfdsakjhfakjhgdfsaghjkgafsdkgkhjfadshgjsfjghksadfgkhjfadsjhgfadsjhgdafskjghasdfghjgkhjafsdghjkfdsaghjkafdgkhjjghkfadsghjkfsadjghkdfsghjkgkhjafsdghjkfsadghjkafksdjkjhdfsaghkjfdsajhgkghjfkadskgjhafdskgjhdafskgkjg&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/2/2e/William_F._Buckley,_Jr._cropped.jpg&quot;&gt;He’s the man&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Personal values provide an internal reference for what is good, beneficial, important, useful, beautiful, desirable, constructive, etc. Values generate behaviour[1] and help solve common human problems for survival by comparative rankings of value, the results of which provide answers to questions of why people do what they do and in what order they choose to do them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over time the public expression of personal values that groups of people find important in their day-to-day lives, lay the foundations of law, custom and tradition. Recent research has thereby stressed the implicit nature of value communication.[2]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Personal values exist in relation to cultural values, either in agreement with or divergence from prevailing norms. A culture is a social system that shares a set of common values, in which such values permit social expectations and collective understandings of the good, beautiful, constructive, etc. Without normative personal values, there would be no cultural reference against which to measure the virtue of individual values and so culture identity would disintegrate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wyatt Woodsmall points out that “‘Criteria’ are used to refer to ‘the standards on which an evaluation is based’.” Values relate then to what one wants and in what order one wants them; criteria can only refer to the evidences for achieving values and act as a comparative standard that one applies in order to evaluate whether goals have been met / values satisfied.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jun 2014 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>/philosophy/2014/06/10/we-need-freedom/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/philosophy/2014/06/10/we-need-freedom/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Buckley redefined conservatism</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;His books, debates, speeches, campaigns, and talk show helped redefined his era. Conservatism will never and can never be the same.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/2/2e/William_F._Buckley,_Jr._cropped.jpg&quot;&gt;He’s the man&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jun 2014 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>/history/2014/06/10/buckley-redefined-conservatism/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/history/2014/06/10/buckley-redefined-conservatism/</guid>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
